Ahh...
the final two Prismatic Blades
are in the hands of my servants.
False dragons!
You seven cosmic frauds!
You've kept me
from what I deserve for eons,
but soon... I will rise!
It's true. My parents are dead.
I saw the headstones myself.
I didn't even get
to say goodbye to them.
[wind blowing]
Aw, man.
Arin, I'm so sorry.
How did...?
I mean, what happened?
The Merge happened!
My parents died
because of what Master Wu did!
If my uncle
really caused the Merge,
I have to believe
he had a good reason.
No reason makes it okay
that my family died!
No, I didn't mean... I just...
But more people will die
if the Forbidden Five
use those blades,
and I need Ras back.
So you want to work with us?
If... if that's okay.
Of course it is.
You're one of us.
I concur.
Was hoping we'd get
to fight together.
I'd rather risk my life
with my best friend
than be safe without you.
Then let's get going.
Not to precipitate
on this procession,
but given the rate
Drix was traveling
with the final two
Prismatic Blades,
catching up to him
before he reaches ThunderFang
is an impossibility.
Impossible as in...
it can't happen?
Yes, I am indeed using
the word "impossible"
to mean "impossible."
I hate Drix.
Second worst time I've had
fighting insects.
First time was
that picnic with Jay.
That was my picnic with Jay.
I didn't invite you!
And I told you not
to rub honey in your hair!
Well, Jay double-dog dared me!
I didn't want to back out
and look uncool.
[Sora] Did you miss this?
"Look uncool"? [laughing]
Did running
through the Monastery
with a swarm of clamp-beetles
on your tail look cool?
Yes, I happen to think that--
[Lloyd] Hold it.
"Through the Monastery."
That's it.
I know how to beat Drix.
[wind howling]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ We fight ♪
♪ Be a ninja
for what's right ♪
[thunderclap]
[♪♪♪]
[Wyldfyre] What do you mean,
"He won't
survive much longer"?
Is that med-bot talk
for "He's definitely
getting better"?
It is not.
It is only a matter of time
before Roby's
vital signs will cease.
The same for the dragon.
Wrong answer.
There has to be
something we can do.
Check all those
boring books again.
We have searched every volume
in the library
several times for any--
Check them again!
Read this. Read that.
Already read it.
Waste of my time.
-[dragon shrieking]
-What--?
You're worried about
your friend too, huh?
Hey! Don't do that!
[squawking]
And... done.
[grumbling contentedly]
Personal reward time!
Mm, candied zip-flies!
Whoa! Wha-wha whoa...
[skidding]
[Mr. Frohicky] Careful!
I just waxed the--
Oh, my mirror finish!
This is a shoes-off temple!
Aah!
Tragically, my polishing skills
are unparalleled.
My apolish-gies.
[chortling]
Master Zane, did you get that?
Wha-ha-ha!
Zane, how long
will Lloyd's plan take?
Set-up should only take
a few minutes,
if all goes as intended.
We have only done this
once before,
and it was not intentionally
planned that time.
A few minutes is all I need.
Whaa!
[Nya] For what?
To build you all something
to even the odds against Drix
and the Dragonians.
Whoa!
You all heard Zane.
We only have a few minutes
to grab supplies, weapons,
anything you need.
Meet back
in the Dragon Stables!
[all slipping]
[sighing]
Well, I wasn't really interested
in personal rewards anyway.
Back to work.
Aah! Ow.
[wistful music playing]
[peaceful music playing]
[laughing]
[munching]
Sorry, just came
to grab some parts.
You know, I missed this swing.
When we didn't know
what happened to you,
I'd sometimes imagine you
sitting there.
It's good to see you back.
I'm not back.
I'm not sure I could ever stay
in Master Wu's monastery again,
knowing what he did.
Arin, I know I lied to you.
I let you think
you hit Ras with the--
Sora, please.
I really need to apologize.
No. You don't.
I'm the one
who needs to apologize.
I was so upset
and... embarrassed.
I overreacted,
when you were just trying
to make me feel good
about myself...
like you always do.
Ever since I was a kid,
I had this dream
of being a Ninja,
and then, somehow,
I got my chance, and...
Sora, do you have any idea
how heartbreaking it is
to find out you're not very good
at the thing you love the most?
But you are a good Ninja.
I'm getting better now.
And Ras, of all people,
is helping me do it.
He showed me that I was
holding myself back.
Holding my emotions back.
You've never held back
how you feel, Arin.
You're the sweetest person
I've ever met.
Not those kind of emotions.
My anger.
The hate I feel deep inside.
The stuff I never show.
It gives you a burst of force.
A fuel I've never had before.
[Sora] Look, you know me.
I'm not the best at training.
That's not true.
Last week, I failed
a Spinjitzu exercise so hard,
I got dizzy
and barfed all over Zane.
Okay. Gross.
It's fine, he froze it
so it was easier to clean up.
The point is
I don't know training,
but I do know you.
There's no way hate and anger
are your greatest strengths.
The Arin I know,
my best friend,
his strength comes
from his kindness.
His generosity.
His hope.
But all that didn't help me.
It helped me.
And it helped everyone
who ever met you.
[running footsteps] Come on.
They've almost got it.
This was truly
an inspired idea, Lloyd.
Only if it works.
You think that thing
will generate enough power?
Like the time you carried
Source Dragon energy.
Not something I plan on doing
ever again, thank you.
I believe I can increase
the power of our Portal Gate
enough to get
all of us and our gear
through to
the First Land Monastery.
Let's just hope it's in
enough time to cut off Drix.
[powering up]
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
These new gliders
are awesome, Sora!
All thanks to Arin
for getting us a prototype!
Any time!
Alright, let's get back
those blades,
stop the Forbidden Five--
[Kai] And get busy
saving the world!
[all] Ninja, go!
...zero research,
no proper testing,
absolutely no prior experience,
your lack of a medical degree
from an accredited university.
Shall I continue with my list
of why this course of action
is ill-advised?
Ill-advised actions are
my favorite kind of actions.
That fact will now go
on the top of my list.
You got any better ideas,
Dr. Robot?
'Cause if I don't
at least try this,
Roby is definitely gonna die.
There are no courses of action
to my knowledge
that would save Roby.
That's what I thought.
Please work.
[crying out]
Blech!
I hate sand on my tongue.
Looks like that's
the center of the winds.
And I'm guessing where
ThunderFang is imprisoned.
If he's still imprisoned.
We'd know if he was free.
[Zane] Then your idea
worked, Lloyd.
Drix has not yet arrived.
How cool is this?
Getting dust
blown in our faces?
I can think of cooler things.
No, being on an adventure
with the Ninja.
Talk about a childhood dream
come true.
[sighing]
I didn't know dreams
could get so complicated.
Blame me, buddy.
For what?
For making you think
Ras's teachings weren't trash.
I'm a stronger Ninja now
than I ever was before.
If you think Ras can teach you
to be a better Ninja than Lloyd,
maybe you don't understand
what a Ninja really is.
[Zane] Everyone...
They're here.
He's waking up!
[Roby] What happened?
I felt like I had a fever.
What happened is
you're beautiful again!
I thought that Kur lady
unstanged my zoot for good.
Yeah, well,
I used my vast knowledge
of science and medicine
to cure your decay.
That is not what happ--
Vast knowledge.
So, how we feeling?
Healed, totally fine?
Uh, I think so,
but why,
you got somewhere to be?
The Ninja ran off to fight
some giant dragon
that shoots chaos storms,
and without me--
There's no way
they can survive
without their best Ninja.
Go!
I'll be fine.
[♪♪♪]
[revving]
[struggling]
Impossible!
I left you behind
in the World Forest!
You couldn't
have beaten me here!
Ninja are full of surprises!
[roaring]
Attack!
I'll go low, you go--
High! Just like
in the Crossroads!
[snarling]
Whaa!
[Kai] Hey!
Don't hog all the fun!
Did you see that?
My Spinjitzu looked
more awesome than usual!
[Lloyd]
It's a First Land thing.
You get used to it!
[Arin] Whoa, whoa, I need him!
Whew!
Sorry, I'm canceling
the appointment
you and those blades have
with ThunderFang.
[chuckling]
The conqueror's path is rarely
a straight line.
[Riyu screeching]
If you did not
understand Riyu,
he said we hypothesized
you would try to escape
via this route.
[Kur] Told you he'd be late.
[Nokt] Late?
I'm betting he failed.
Arin! Free your master!
[Drix crying out]
[Lloyd] Thought
you might do that!
One down, one to go!
[Lloyd] Ninja, we got this!
[laughing]
[gasping]
That belongs to us!
Those things aren't yours
just 'cause
you want them really bad, Rox.
I'm not great at math,
but we are way outnumbered here.
Time for a rematch, girl.
Remind you of that time
I saved you from those bullies?
Uh... why you gotta
bring that up?
Now, who do we have here?
I brought you a present, Nokt.
Priorities, priorities.
I can take him from here.
[grunting]
No! Focus on what matters!
Oh, so impulsive,
and so foolish.
Waah!
Ugh!
I've been waiting
a long time for this.
[grunting]
I have no interest
in fighting someone weakened...
like you did to me
with that control collar.
I should never have freed you.
Aw, that hurts.
Because if you didn't free me,
we'd never have moments
like this!
[grunting]
[Drix crying out]
[Arin] Sorry, lady!
You little runt!
Don't you know who
you are messing w--
unh!
I've got it!
[Arin] Riyu!
Arin, we'll hold them off!
Get back to the Monastery
with those!
On it!
Ras... no...
Now, Lord Ras,
let me show you
what real power can--
[grunting]
Arin, no!
Gaah!
Now the little underling
wants to save his master?
Let him go!
I don't take orders from you.
I don't take orders
from anyone.
Then I'll force you to stop.
[laughing]
I see you're a comedian.
It's not fun--
[crying out]
[laughing]
Come, my brethren!
It is time!
[Kai crying out]
Come on! We've gotta stop them!
[struggling]
[shrieking]
[grunting]
[screaming]
[crying out]
[impact]
Pixal! Zane! Hold tight!
[pounding]
Aah!
[smashing]
[roaring]
The powers you promised...
My minions,
you are such fools.
If you really trusted me,
you are even more pathetic
than I realized.
[roaring]
[screaming]
[♪♪♪]